Guide to the Fidelis Zitterbart Manuscripts, 1868-1915 SC.1967.02
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Quintett: [no.] 11 for 2 Violins, Viola, Violoncello and Piano in D Minor, March 25, 1907; 1 score (60 p.), violin 1 part (7 p.), violin 2 part (7 p.), viola part (7 p.), and violincello part (7 p.) (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Quintett: [no.] 11 - Parts: Violoncello, March 25, 1907; 5.
- Quintett: [no.] 12 for 2 Violins, Viola, Violoncello and Piano in F Minor, February 29, 1908; 1 score (53 p.), violin 1 part (10 p.), violin 2 part 9 p.), viola part (9 p.), and violincello part (9 p.) (Box 26, Folder 1)
  The number "12" written in pencil on cover and parts.
  - Quintett: [no.] 12 - Score, February 29, 1908; 1.
  - Quintett: [no.] 12 - Parts: Violin 1, February 29, 1908; 2.
  - Quintett: [no.] 12 - Parts: Violin 2, February 29, 1908; 3.
  - Quintett: [no.] 12 - Parts: Viola, February 29, 1908; 4.
  - Quintett: [no.] 12 - Parts: Violoncello, February 29, 1908; 5.
- Quintett: [no.] 13 for 2 Violins, Viola, Violoncello and Piano in Bb Major, The chimes, March 22, 1908; 1 score (45 p.), violin 1 part (7 p.), violin 2 part (7 p.), viola part (7 p.), and violincello part (7 p.) (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Quintett: [no.] 13 - Score, March 22, 1908; 1.
  - Quintett: [no.] 13 - Parts: Violin 1, March 22, 1908; 2.
  - Quintett: [no.] 13 - Parts: Violin 2, March 22, 1908; 3.
  - Quintett: [no.] 13 - Parts: Viola, March 22, 1908; 4.
  - Quintett: [no.] 13 - Parts: Violoncello, March 22, 1908; 5.
- Quintett: [no.] 14 for 2 Violins, Viola, Violoncello and Piano in G Minor, April 12, 1912; 1 score (38 p.), violin 1 part (6 p.), violin 2 part (6 p.), viola part (6 p.), and violincello part (5 p.) (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Quintett: [no.] 14 - Score, April 12, 1912; 1.
  - Quintett: [no.] 14 - Parts: Violin 1, April 12, 1912; 2.
  - Quintett: [no.] 14 - Parts: Violin 2, April 12, 1912; 3.
  - Quintett: [no.] 14 - Parts: Viola, April 12, 1912; 4.
  - Quintett: [no.] 14 - Parts: Violoncello, April 12, 1912; 5.
- Quintett: [no.] 15 for 2 Violins, Viola, Violoncello and Piano in D Minor, January 25, 1915; 1 score (36 p.), violin 1 part (7 p.), violin 2 part (5 p.), viola part (5 p.), and violincello part (5 p.) (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Quintett: [no.] 15 - Score, January 25, 1915; 1.
  - Quintett: [no.] 15 - Parts: Violin 1, January 25, 1915; 2.
  - Quintett: [no.] 15 - Parts: Violin 2, January 25, 1915; 3.
  - Quintett: [no.] 15 - Parts: Viola, January 25, 1915; 4.
  - Quintett: [no.] 15 - Parts: Violoncello, January 25, 1915; 5.
- Nixenrache: Fantasiegemälde, October 22, 1885; 1 score (14 p.), flute part (3 p.), violine 1 part (4 p.), violin 2 part (3 p.), viola part (3 p.), violoncello part (3 p.), basso part (2 p.), and piano part (5 p.) (Box 26, Folder 5)
  Score in oblong format in pencil; Parts in upright format in black ink. Text of poem by Hermann von Beguignolles on inside of wrapper for parts.
  - Nixenrache - Score, October 22, 1885; 1.
  - Nixenrache - Parts: Flute, October 22, 1885; 2.
  - Nixenrache - Parts: Violin 1, October 22, 1885; 3.
  - Nixenrache - Parts: Violin 2, October 22, 1885; 4.
  - Nixenrache - Parts: Viola, October 22, 1885; 5.
  - Nixenrache - Parts: Violoncello, October 22, 1885; 6.
  - Nixenrache - Parts: Basso, October 22, 1885; 7.
  - Nixenrache - Parts: Piano, October 22, 1885; 8.
- The Barque of Dreams: Fantasy Poetic: for 2 Violins, Viola, Flute, Oboe, Piano primo, Piano secondo, 1902; 1 score (30 p.), flute part (3 p.), oboe part (3 p.), violin 1 part (3 p.), violin 2 (3 p.), viola part (3 p.), and piano secondo part (4 p.) (Box 26, Folder 6)
  On cover and t.p.: Poetry by Clinton Scollard. Poem (printed) pasted in before score. On caption: In A minor; in 1 part.
  - The Barque of Dreams - Score, 1902; 1.
  - The Barque of Dreams - Parts: Flute, 1902; 2.
  - The Barque of Dreams - Parts: Oboe, 1902; 3.
  - The Barque of Dreams - Parts: Violin 1, 1902; 4.
  - The Barque of Dreams - Parts: Violin 2, 1902; 5.
  - The Barque of Dreams - Parts: Viola, 1902; 6.
  - The Barque of Dreams - Parts: Piano Secondo, 1902; 7.
- Cradlesong: for 2 Violins, Viola, 2 Flutes, and Piano in G Major, August 20, 1904; 1 score (5 p.), flute 1 part (1 p.), flute 2 part (1 p.), violin 1 part (1 p.), violin 2 part (1 p.), and viola part (1 p.) (Box 26, Folder 7)
  Pasted on top of wrapper: 7.
  - Cradlesong - Score, August 20, 1904; 1.
  - Cradlesong - Parts: Flute 1, August 20, 1904; 2.
  - Cradlesong - Parts: Flute 2, August 20, 1904; 3.
  - Cradlesong - Parts: Violin 1, August 20, 1904; 4.
  - Cradlesong - Parts: Violin 2, August 20, 1904; 5.
  - Cradlesong - Parts: Viola, August 20, 1904; 6.
- Hallowe'en Freaks: Morceau: for Violin, Viola, Piano, October 30, 1913; 1 score (10 p.), violin part (2 p.), and viola part (2 p.) (Box 26, Folder 8)
  Image of witch on broom pasted on cover.
  - Hallowe'en Freaks - Score, October 30, 1913; 1.
  - Hallowe'en Freaks - Parts: Violin, October 30, 1913; 2.
  - Hallowe'en Freaks - Parts: Viola, October 30, 1913; 3.
- The Snake Charmer: Morceau: for Violin, Viola, and Piano, October 28, 1913; 1 score (8 p.), violin part (2 p.), and viola part (2 p.) (Box 26, Folder 9)
  Image on snake charmer with decorative border in blue pasted on cover.
  - The Snake Charmer - Score, October 28, 1913; 1.
  - The Snake Charmer - Parts: Violin, October 28, 1913; 2.
  - The Snake Charmer - Parts: Viola, October 28, 1913; 3.
- Sonate-Moderne: [no.] 1: für Violine und Piano: in A Dur, November 11, 1887; 1 score (16 p.), and violin part (5 p.) (Box 27, Folder 1)
  Some bleed-through of ink in score.
  - Sonate-Moderne - Score, November 11, 1887; 1.
  - Sonate-Moderne - Parts: Violine, November 11, 1887; 2.
- Sonate: [no.] 2 for Violin and Piano in F Major, August 1, 1888; 2 scores (17, and 22 p.), and 2 violine parts, (each 6 p.) (Box 27, Folder 2)
  The number "23" written in pencil on t.p. The composer has rearranged the movements of the work: in the score, Movement 3, Scherzando is corrected in pencil as movement 4; the new movement 3, Scherzo is in pencil and laid inside the score; in the violin part, movement 2, Adagio is corrected as movement 3; and movement 3 (scherzando in score) is corrected as movement 4 and renamed Allegro giojoso; there is no separate violin part for the new movement 3; that part is only in the ms score. The score has numerous corrections mainly to the piano part in pencil and black ink. Date at the end of the score is 11/03/1888. There is an undated 2nd copy of the piece with the number "2" pasted on the t.p. It has the correct names for each movement, but movement 2 is copied after movement 3 in violin part.
  - Sonate: [no.] 2 - Score 1, August 1, 1888; 1.
  - Sonate: [no.] 2 - Score 2, August 1, 1888; 2.
  - Sonate: [no.] 2 - Violine, August 1, 1888; 3.
  - Sonate: [no.] 2 - Violin, August 1, 1888; 4.
- Sonata in E Major: for Violin and Piano: No. 3, 2 scores (34, and 29 p.), and 2 violin parts, (each 10 p.) (Box 27, Folder 3)
  2 copies each of score and violin part.
  - Sonata in E Major - Score 1, 1.
  - Sonata in E Major - Score 2, 2.
  - Sonata in E Major - Violin, 3.
  - Sonata in E Major - Violin, 4.
- Sonate: [no.] 4 for Violin and Piano in E Minor, 1 score (23 p.), and violin part (7 p.) (Box 27, Folder 4)
  Minor corrections in pencil in score and part.
  - Sonate: [no.] 4 - Score, 1.
  - Sonate: [no.] 4 - Parts: Violin, 2.
- Sonata: [no.] 5 for Violin and Piano in D Minor, The Poet, February 8, 1900; 1 score (23 p.), and violin part (7 p.) (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Sonata: [no.] 5 - Score, February 8, 1900; 1.
  - Sonata: [no.] 5 - Parts: Violin, February 8, 1900; 2.
- Sonata: [no.] 6 for Violin and Piano in Bb Major, Agnes, 1 score (21 p.), and violin part (7 p.) (Box 27, Folder 6)
  At head of title: To Mrs. Agnes Braun. Photograph pasted on caption (Agnes Braun?). Subject written in red ink on caption and in black ink on part: (a- g - g).
  - Sonata: [no.] 6 - Score, 1.
  - Sonata: [no.] 6 - Parts: Violin, 2.
- Sonate in C Dur: für Violine und Piano: No. 6, December 19, 1867; 1 score (23 p.), and violine part (7 p.) (Box 27, Folder 7)
  "Op. 42" on t.p. Location: New York
  - Sonate in C Dur - Score, December 19, 1867; 1.
  - Sonate in C Dur - Parts: Violine, December 19, 1867; 2.
- Sonata: no.] 7 for Violin and Piano in G Major, Florence, March 3, 1900; 1 score (21 p.), and violin part (7 p.) (Box 27, Folder 8)
  At head of title: To Miss Florence Zitterbart. Photo of women (Florence?) pasted in on caption.
  - Sonata: no.] 7 - Score, March 3, 1900; 1.
  - Sonata: no.] 7 - Parts: Violin, March 3, 1900; 2.
- Sonata No. 8 for Violin and Piano in D Minor, Beatrice, [1901?]; 1 score (22 p.), and violin part (8 p.) (Box 27, Folder 9)
  At head of title: To Miss Beatrice Zitterbart.
  - Sonata No. 8 - Score, [1901?]; 1.
  - Sonata No. 8 - Parts: Violin, [1901?]; 2.
- Sonate in D Dur: für Violine und Piano: No. 9, April 15, 1868; 1 score (24 p.), and violin part (7 p.) (Box 27, Folder 10)
  "Op. 45" on t.p. Corrections in pencil in score and violin part. Location: New York
  - Sonate in D Dur - Score, April 15, 1868; 1.
  - Sonate in D Dur - Parts: Violin, April 15, 1868; 2.
- Sonata No. 9 for Violin and Piano in A Minor, December 6, 1901; 1 score (27 p.), and violin part (9 p.) (Box 27, Folder 11)
  At head of title: To my friend / Harry Hetzel.
  - Sonata No. 9 - Score, December 6, 1901; 1.
  - Sonata No. 9 - Parts: Violin, December 6, 1901; 2.
- Sonate in F Dur: für Violine und Piano: No. 10, August 1, 1888; 1 score (40 p.), and violine part (15 p.) (Box 27, Folder 12)
  "Op. 86" on t.p. "Op. 57" on violin part. At head of title: To Phillip Faerber Esq. Title on caption: Grosse Sonate. Damage on last page of violin part obscures musical line at that point. Location: New York
  - Sonate in F Dur - Score, August 1, 1888; 1.
  - Sonate in F Dur - Violine, August 1, 1888; 2.
- Sonata: [no.] 10 [for Violin and Piano] in Bb Minor, Appassionato, March 10, 1902; 1 score (27 p.), and violin part (10 p.) (Box 28, Folder 1)
  Illustration of irises with decorative border pasted in upper left hand cover of cover.
  - Sonata: [no.] 10 - Score, March 10, 1902; 1.
  - Sonata: [no.] 10 - Parts: Violin, March 10, 1902; 2.
- Sonata: [no.] 11 for Violin and Piano in D Minor, Romantique, April 15, 1902; 1 score (25 p.), and violin part (9 p.) (Box 28, Folder 2)
  "Romantique" and "in D minor" in red ink on cover.
  - Sonata: [no.] 11 - Score, April 15, 1902; 1.
  - Sonata: [no.] 11 - Violin, April 15, 1902; 2.
- Sonata No. 12 [for Violin and Piano] in Eb Major, November 1, 1903; 1 score (21 p.), and violin part (7 p.) (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Sonata No. 12 - Score, November 1, 1903; 1.
  - Sonata No. 12 - Violin, November 1, 1903; 2.
- Sonata: [no.] 13 for Violin and Piano in A Minor, Rumpelstitlzkin, November 16, 1903; 1 score (27 p.), and violin part (8 p.) (Box 28, Folder 4)
  Illustration in black and white of woman and a spinning wheel in foreground, and Rumpelstilskin coming in door at back with decorative border in red pasted at top of cover.
  - Sonata: [no.] 13 - Score, November 16, 1903; 1.
  - Sonata: [no.] 13 - Parts: Violin, November 16, 1903; 2.
- Sonata No. 14 for Violin and Piano in G Minor: FÉO, December 4, 1903; 1 score (24 p.), and violin part (8 p.) (Box 28, Folder 5)
  Illustrated cover: images of women reading and playing the syrinx on left and right; image of woman between these images with "Féo " as caption below.
  - Sonata No. 14 - Score, December 4, 1903; 1.
  - Sonata No. 14 - Parts: Violin, December 4, 1903; 2.
- Sonata: [no.] 16 for Violin and Piano in G Minor, The Maid of the Mist, September 4, 1904; 1 score (25 p.), and violin part (8 p.) (Box 28, Folder 7)
  Illustration in black and blue ink of woman with pail in her right hand walking through a forest pasted on cover.
  - Sonata: [no.] 16 - Score, September 4, 1904; 1.
  - Sonata: [no.] 16 - Violin, September 4, 1904
- Sonata No. 17 for Violin and Piano in C Major, Beethoven, September 20, 1904; 1 score (24 p.), and violin part (10 p.) (Box 28, Folder 8)
  Illustrated cover: image of Beethoven strolling in center at top of page; each corner of page has watercolor flowers on tissue paper pasted in.
  - Sonata No. 17 - Score, September 20, 1904; 1.
  - Sonata No. 17 - Parts: Violin, September 20, 1904; 2.
- Sonata: [no.] 18 for Violin and Piano in Bb Major, March 15, 1905; 1 score (31 p.), and violin part (10 p.) (Box 28, Folder 9)
  Illustrations of flowers and decorative cartouche pasted in on cover.
  - Sonata: [no.] 18 - Score, March 15, 1905; 1.
  - Sonata: [no.] 18 - Parts: Violin, March 15, 1905; 2.
- Sonata No. 19 for Violin and Piano in G Minor, July 31, 1905; 1 score (31 p.), and violin part (10 p.) (Box 28, Folder 10)
  At head of title: To Carl Braun, Jr. Additional measures of music in gutters on p. 30 of score. Some pages of score had bottom corner folded; perhaps manuscript was used in performance.
  - Sonata No. 19 - Score, July 31, 1905; 1.
  - Sonata No. 19 - Violin, July 31, 1905
- Sonata: [no.] 20 for Violin and Piano in Bb Major, November 25, 1905; 1 score (27 p.), and violin part (8 p.) (Box 28, Folder 11)
  At head of title: To Mrs. Agnes Braun. Photograph of woman (Agnes Braun?) with green border pasted in on cover.
  - Sonata: [no.] 20 - Score, November 25, 1905; 1.
  - Sonata: [no.] 20 - Parts: Violin, November 25, 1905; 2.
- Sonata No. 21 for Violin and Piano in Ab Major, La Belle Dame Sans Merci, September 5, 1906; 1 score (31 p.), and violin part (10 p.) (Box 28, Folder 12)
  Illustrated cover: image of woman in contemplative stance pasted on cover. Watercolor on tissue paper.
  - Sonata No. 21 - Score, September 5, 1906; 1.
  - Sonata No. 21 - Parts - Violin, September 5, 1906; 2.
- Sonata: [no.] 21a for Violin and Piano in B Minor, January 5, 1910 (Box 28, Folder 13)
  At head of title: To Mr. Carl Braun Jr. Two copies of score and violin part. Second copy of score (unnumbered) and violin part is only the first movement.
  - Sonata: [no.] 21a - Score, January 5, 1910; 1.
  - Sonata: [no.] 21a - Parts: Violin, January 5, 1910; 3.
- Sonata No. 22 for Violin and Piano F Major, November 16, 1910; 1 score (25 p.), and violin part (7 p.) (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Sonata No. 22 - Score, November 16, 1910; 1.
  - Sonata No. 22 - Parts: Violin, November 16, 1910; 2.
- Sonata: [no.] 24 for Violin and Piano in G Major, January 15, 1912; 1 score (22 p.), and violin part (7 p.) (Box 29, Folder 2)
  The number "24" written in pencil at top of cover of score and in red pencil on violin part.
  - Sonata: [no.] 24 - Score, January 15, 1912; 1.
  - Sonata: [no.] 24 - Parts: Violin, January 15, 1912; 2.
- Sonata for Violin and Piano in D Major, The Autosubject, August 10, 1910; 1 score (9 p.), and violin part (3 p.) (Box 29, Folder 3)
  The number "30" penciled in on t.p. and violin part.
  - Sonata for Violin and Piano in D Major - Score, August 10, 1910; 1.
  - Sonata for Violin and Piano in D Major - Parts: Violin, August 10, 1910; 2.
- Souvenir de Carl Maria de Weber: in Sonata Form: for Violin and Piano: in A Minor, October 10, 1912; 1 score (22 p.), and violin part (7 p.) (Box 29, Folder 4)
  Corrections in heavy black ink in piano part in score, esp. p. 6 & p. 8. Some spotting in score due to ms not being completely dry before the composer went to the verso of the next page of ms.
  - Souvenir de Carl Maria de Weber - Score, October 10, 1912
  - Souvenir de Carl Maria de Weber - Violin, October 10, 1912; 2.
- Sonata quasi Fantasy for Violin and Piano in F Minor, August 19, 1913; 1 score (23 p.), and violin part (8 p.) (Box 29, Folder 5)
  The number "25" penciled in on t.p. and in red pencil on violin part.
  - Sonata quasi Fantasy - Score, August 19, 1913; 1.
  - Sonata quasi Fantasy - Parts: Violin, August 19, 1913; 2.
- Sonata No. 2 [for] Viola and Piano in G Minor, August 31, 1897; 1 score (24 p.), and viola part (8 p.) (Box 29, Folder 6)
  At head of title: To Carl Braun, Jr. The number "22" pasted in on score and part, and scratched out in pencil. The number "2" in ink on viola part. Score has numerous corrections and pasteovers.
  - Sonata No. 2 - Score, August 31, 1897; 1.
  - Sonata No. 2 - Parts: Viola, August 31, 1897; 2.
- Sonate: [no.] 20 für Viola und Piano in F Dur, Die 300 Jährige, May 24, 1886; 1 score (9 p.), and viola part (3 p.) (Box 29, Folder 7)
  The number "543" written in pencil on score. The number "20" pasted in on score and part. Title on score: Sonate in F dur no. 2. Title on part: Sonate in F dur no. 2: in 2 Sätzen. At end of score and part: Der dritte Satz bleibt weg. Die 300 Jährigen sind mit 2 Sätzen zufrieden. Contents. 1. Allegro -- 2. Adagio quasi marcia sombre.
  - Sonate: [no.] 20 - Score, May 24, 1886; 1.
  - Sonate: [no.] 20 - Parts: Viola, May 24, 1886; 2.
- Sonata: [no.] 21 [for] Viola and Piano in A Minor, May 24, 1875; 1 score (32 p.), and viola part (11 p.) (Box 29, Folder 8)
  The number "542" written in pencil on score. The numbers "21: and "1" pasted in on score and part. At head of title: To Mr. George Matzka. Location: New York. Contents: 1. Allegro appassianato -- 2. Adagio -- 3. Scherzo vivace -- 4. Allegro con spirito quasi presto.
  - Sonata: [no.] 21 - Score, May 24, 1875; 1.
  - Sonata: [no.] 21 - Parts: Viola, May 24, 1875; 2.
- Sonate: No. 1: in für Viola und Piano A Moll, May 24, 1875; 1 score (14 p.), and viola part (11 p.) (Box 29, Folder 9)
  An earlier, working copy of this piece. There are numerous corrections in pencil. The score and part are brittle and some of the music is missing.
  - Sonate: No. 1 - Score, May 24, 1875; 1.
  - Sonate: No. 1 - Parts: Viola, May 24, 1875; 2.
- Sonata: [no.] 23 [for] Viola et Piano: in A Minor, November 21, 1900; 1 score (24 p.), and viola part (10 p.) (Box 29, Folder 10)
  The number "541" written in pencil on t.p. The numbers "3" and "23" pasted in on score and part. Title on score and part: Sonata no. 3 in A minor. Contents: 1. Allegro passione-- 2. Adagio pathetiqué -- 3. Scherzo presto-- 4. Finale: Allegro agitato.
  - Sonata: [no.] 23 - Score, November 21, 1900; 1.
  - Sonata: [no.] 23 - Parts: Viola, November 21, 1900; 2.
- Sonata: [no.] 26 for Viola and Piano in C Minor, The Gladiator, March 3, 1903; 1 score (38 p.), and viola part (12 p.) (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Sonata: [no.] 26 - Score, March 3, 1903; 1.
  - Sonata: [no.] 26 - Parts: Viola, March 3, 1903; 2.
- Sonata: [no.] 27 for Viola and Piano in C Minor, January 10, 1904; 1 score (23 p.), and viola part (9 p.) (Box 29, Folder 12)
  The number "539" written in pencil on cover. The number "27" pasted in on cover and part. The number "5" pasted in on score and part. Title on part: Sonata no. 5 in C minor. Contents: 1. Allegro con moto -- 2. Adagio consolato-- 3. Allegretto scherzando -- 4. Finale: Allegro appassianato.
  - Sonata: [no.] 27 - Score, January 10, 1904; 1.
  - Sonata: [no.] 27 - Parts: Viola, January 10, 1904; 2.
- Sonata: [no.] 28 for Viola and Piano in E Minor, January 20, 1904; 1 score (32 p.), and viola part (10 p.) (Box 29, Folder 13)
  The number "538" written in pencil on cover. The number "28" pasted in on cover and part. The number "6" pasted in on score and part. Contents: 1. Allegro-vivace et agitato -- 2. Andante-moso et grazioso -- 3. Scherzo presto -- 4. Finale: Allegro vigoroso.
  - Sonata: [no.] 28 - Score, January 20, 1904; 1.
  - Sonata: [no.] 28 - Parts: Viola, January 20, 1904; 2.
- Sonata: [no.] 29 for Viola and Piano in D Minor, February 7, 1905; 1 score (42 p.), and viola part (11 p.) (Box 30, Folder 1)
  The number "537" written in pencil on cover. The number "29" pasted in on cover and part. The number"7" pasted in on score and part. Picture of small flower pasted on cover. Contents: 1. Allegro appassianato-- 2. Adagio dramatiqué -- 3. Allegro scherzando -- 4. Finale: Allegro-agitato quasi presto.
  - Sonata: [no.] 29 - Score, February 7, 1905; 1.
  - Sonata: [no.] 29 - Parts: Viola, February 7, 1905; 2.
- Sonata: [no.] 30 for Viola and Piano in Eb Major, Panoramic, March 2, 1905; 1 score (37 p.), violin part (9 p.), and viola part (9 p.) (Box 30, Folder 2)
  The number "536" written in pencil on cover. The number "30" pasted in cover and part. The number "8" is pasted on parts. Violin part included is the viola part written in G clef. Contents: 1. At dusk (Allegro-moderato et molto-passione -- 2. Madonna (Adagio cantabile)-- 3. Scena dramatiqué (Scherzo-serioso. Allegro-agitato) -- 4. Finale: The automobile ride (Allegro Vivace).
  - Sonata: [no.] 30 - Score, March 2, 1905; 1.
  - Sonata: [no.] 30 - Parts: Violin, March 2, 1905; 2.
  - Sonata: [no.] 30 - Parts: Viola, March 2, 1905; 3.
- Sonata: [no.] 33 for Viola and Piano in A Minor, November 17, 1905; 1 score (25 p.), and viola part (7 p.) (Box 30, Folder 3)
  The number "535" written in pencil on cover. The number "33" pasted in on cover and part. At head of title: To Mrs. Florene James Black. Photograph of a woman (Florene James Balck?) pasted in on cover. Contents: 1. Allegro con moto -- 2. Adagio-cantabile quasi romanza -- 3. Scherzo-giojoso molto allegro -- 4. Finale: Allegro affettuoso.
  - Sonata: [no.] 33 - Score, November 17, 1905; 1.
  - Sonata: [no.] 33 - Parts: Viola, November 17, 1905; 2.
- Sonata: [no.] 35 for Viola and Piano in C Major, December 9, 1905; 1 score (29 p.), and viola part (11 p.) (Box 30, Folder 4)
  The number "534" written in pencil on cover. The number "11" pasted in on cover and part, is crossed out and the number "37" written in red pencil, Contents: 1. Allegro-maestoso et vigoroso -- 2. Introductione et romanza -- 3. Tema con variazione et coda andante con moto -- 4. Finale: Allegro con brio.
  - Sonata: [no.] 35 - Score, December 9, 1905; 1.
  - Sonata: [no.] 35 - Parts: Viola, December 9, 1905; 2.
- Sonata: [no.] 36 for Viola and Piano in B Minor, March 9, 1906; 1 score (29 p.), and viola part (9 p.) (Box 30, Folder 5)
  The number "533" written in pencil on cover. The number "12" pasted in on cover and part, is crossed out with the number "37" written in red pencil. Contents: 1. Allegro con brio -- 2. Adagio sentimentale -- 3. Allegretto et mMolto-giojoso -- 4. Finale: Allegro-moderato et affettuoso.
  - Sonata: [no.] 36 - Score, March 9, 1906; 1.
  - Sonata: [no.] 36 - Parts: Viola, March 9, 1906; 2.
- Sonata: [no.] 37 for Viola and Piano in Ab Major, December 8, 1910; 1 score (31 p.), and viola part (10 p.) (Box 30, Folder 6)
  The number "532" written in pencil on cover. The number" 37" written in red pencil on cover and part. Dates of composition vary on each movement. Contents: 1. Allegro appassianato 12/8/1910) -- 2. Adagio symphoniqué (12/7/1910) -- 3. Scherzo vivace (12/17/1910) -- 4. Allegro-con-moto.
  - Sonata: [no.] 37 - Score, December 8, 1910; 1.
  - Sonata: [no.] 37 - Parts: Viola, December 8, 1910; 2.
- Souvenir de Anton Rubinstein: Quartettsatz für Violine 1mo, Violine 2ndo, Viola, und Violoncello, violine 1 part (1 p.), violine 2 part (1 p.), viola part (1 p.), and violoncello part (1 p.) (Box 30, Folder 7)
  The word "Souvenir" is corrected on t.p. and on caption of each part.
  - Souvenir de Anton Rubinstein - Parts: Violine 1, 1.
  - Souvenir de Anton Rubinstein - Parts: Violine 2, 2.
  - Souvenir de Anton Rubinstein - Parts: Viola, 3.
  - Souvenir de Anton Rubinstein - Parts: Violoncello, 4.
- Scherzo-Minuet: Anita: from Poetic Suite, violin 1 part (1 p.), violin 2 part (1 p.), viola part (1 p.), and violoncello part (1 p.) (Box 30, Folder 8)
  Transposed to D major. Orginal in E-flat major
  - Scherzo-Minuet - Parts: Violin 1, 1.
  - Scherzo-Minuet - Parts: Violin 2, 2.
  - Scherzo-Minuet - Parts: Viola, 3.
  - Scherzo-Minuet - Parts: Violoncello, 4.
- The Legend of the Pied Piper of Hamelin: Fantasy for Flute, 2 Violins, Viola, and Piano: [in A Minor], February 15, 1905; 1 score (37 p.), flute part (6 p.), violin 1 part (7 p.), violin 2 part (6 p.), and viola part (6 p.) (Box 30, Folder 9)